<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: SXSimpleClippedImage | Noise & Heat]]></title>
  <link href="http://noiseandheat.com/blog/categories/sxsimpleclippedimage/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://noiseandheat.com/"/>
  <updated>2012-11-16T00:01:02+00:00</updated>
  <id>http://noiseandheat.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[David Wagner]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Simple Clipped Image for Sparrow Framework]]></title>
    <link href="http://noiseandheat.com/blog/2011/07/simple-clipped-image-for-sparrow-framework/"/>
    <updated>2011-07-06T23:52:00+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://noiseandheat.com/blog/2011/07/simple-clipped-image-for-sparrow-framework</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><a href="https://github.com/mnem/SXSimpleClippedImage/"><img class="right" src="/images/0_article_thumb5.png" width="200" height="130"></a></p>

<p>I'm currently playing around with the rather fine iOS game engine,
<a href="http://www.sparrow-framework.org/">Sparrow Framework</a>.</p>

<p>I had been aware of it for a while, but hadn't really got my hands dirty using
it. However I've recently resolved to work on a few side projects with <a href="https://twitter.com/dwlt">Dave Thomson</a> who waxed lyrical about it's ease of use,
so I decided to learn a bit more about it.</p>

<!--more-->


<p>It's great. No, really, it is. It's fairly lightweight, but quite powerful -
it uses a display model similar to Flash so anyone who has coded in AS3 will
immediately feel at home. I'm looking forward to mastering it, and I suspect
I'll be writing a few posts about using it in the games I'm working on.</p>

<p>However, the lightweightness does mean that sometimes simple features you want
to use aren't there. That's not a problem though - it has a small but vibrant
developer community, and the main website encourages people to add extensions
to it. These are essentially classes or simple modifications posted as
<a href="http://gist.github.com/">gists</a>, or sometimes provided as full
<a href="http://github.com/">github</a> repositories, which are all linked to from the
<a href="http://wiki.sparrow-framework.org/extensions/start">extensions</a> section in
the Sparrow wiki. You just grab the files and add them to your own project.</p>

<p>So, here is my first extension:</p>

<ul>
<li><a href="https://github.com/mnem/SXSimpleClippedImage/tree/master/Classes">https://github.com/mnem/SXSimpleClippedImage/tree/master/Classes</a></li>
</ul>


<p>It's a simple extension to the <a href="http://doc.sparrow-framework.org/core/Classes/SPImage.html">SPImage</a>
class so that you can display only a sub-region of the image texture associated
with the <a href="http://doc.sparrow-framework.org/core/Classes/SPImage.html">SPImage</a>.
If you've used Flash, you can think of it as a rectangular mask for the image data.
The main difference is that as you move the mask from <code>0,0</code> in the
<a href="http://doc.sparrow-framework.org/core/Classes/SPImage.html">SPImage</a>,
the remaining image data is drawn starting at the current location of the
<a href="http://doc.sparrow-framework.org/core/Classes/SPImage.html">SPImage</a>
object on the screen. That probably makes no sense, but if you play with it,
you'll see what I mean. There's a reasonable chance that behaviour will
sufficiently annoy me in the near future that I'll fix it.</p>

<p>For an example on how to use it, clone or browse the project repository and
have a look in <a href="https://github.com/mnem/SXSimpleClippedImage/blob/master/TestClasses/Game.m">TestClasses/game.m</a>.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
