<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Colour | Noise & Heat]]></title>
  <link href="http://noiseandheat.github.com/blog/categories/colour/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://noiseandheat.github.com/"/>
  <updated>2012-11-16T00:08:28+00:00</updated>
  <id>http://noiseandheat.github.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[David Wagner]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[OS X Lion Terminal Colours]]></title>
    <link href="http://noiseandheat.github.com/blog/2011/12/os-x-lion-terminal-colours/"/>
    <updated>2011-12-03T21:25:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://noiseandheat.github.com/blog/2011/12/os-x-lion-terminal-colours</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://www.vim.org/scripts/script.php?script_id=1349"><img class="right" src="/images/terminal_colours.png" width="200" height="130"></a></p>

<p>OS X is awesome for command line stuff, that's why <a href="http://xkcd.com/378/">real programmers</a>
love it. But some of the defaults Apple have used make me sad. Where are all
the colours? I <em>demand</em> my <code>ls</code> command be pretty and colourful! Why is Vim
so bland? While we're at it, can't ping lick my eyeballs more?</p>

<!--more-->


<p>Good news: yes, they can! I've stuck some tips together so I can remind
myself what to do when I inevitably reinstall my system for some pointless
reason, and for any new Mac users out there. It is near peak commercial
season after all, and I'm sure you've been good little boys and girls.</p>

<p>Let's start with the simple things.</p>

<h2>Making <code>ls</code> and <code>grep</code> Colourful</h2>

<p>Add these lines to your <code>.bash_profile</code> file which is in your home directory:</p>

<p>``` bash ~/.bash_profile</p>

<h1>Tell ls to be colourful</h1>

<p>export CLICOLOR=1</p>

<h1>Tell grep to highlight matches</h1>

<p>export GREP_OPTIONS='--color=auto'
```</p>

<p>Now when you use <code>ls</code>, folders and executables will appear in different
colours from normal files, and when you use grep to find text in files, the
matches will be highlighted.</p>

<p>You can change the colours used by <code>ls</code> via the <code>LSCOLORS</code> environment
variable. For example:</p>

<p>``` bash ~/.bash_profile</p>

<h1>Tell ls to be colourful</h1>

<p>export CLICOLOR=1
export LSCOLORS=Exfxcxdxbxegedabagacad</p>

<h1>Tell grep to highlight matches</h1>

<p>export GREP_OPTIONS='--color=auto'
```</p>

<p>Here's a handy website you can use to define your <code>LSCOLORS</code> scheme:
<a href="http://geoff.greer.fm/lscolors/">http://geoff.greer.fm/lscolors/</a>. It also
generates <code>LS_COLORS</code> definitions, useful if you're a Linux user. One thing
to note, though, is that the colours you will see in your terminal depend on
the particular theme you are using. Which brings me to my next tip.</p>

<h2>Using A Better Terminal Theme</h2>

<p>If you haven't changed the default terminal theme you must still be gazing
in to the snowy wasteland that is the default. This is insane. Programmers
are incompatible with white backgrounds. Er, except in blogs. <em>*cough*</em></p>

<p>Changing the terminal theme is marginally trickier than it should be. Here's
how you do it:</p>

<ol>
<li>Go to <code>Terminal</code> &rarr; <code>Preferences…</code></li>
<li>Select the <code>Settings</code> group.</li>
<li>Pick something nice that doesn't sear your retinas.</li>
<li>At the bottom of the list box, click <code>Default</code> so that new terminals will
open with the selected colour scheme.</li>
</ol>


<p>Anything other than the default is a good start, but there are better themes out there than those bundled
with Lion. At the moment, my colour scheme of choice is <a href="http://ethanschoonover.com/solarized">Solarized</a>.
You can get a <a href="http://ethanschoonover.com/solarized">Solarized</a> scheme for
OS X's Terminal from here:</p>

<ul>
<li><a href="https://github.com/altercation/solarized/tree/master/osx-terminal.app-colors-solarized">https://github.com/altercation/solarized/tree/master/osx-terminal.app-colors-solarized</a></li>
</ul>


<p>If you are running <strong>Lion</strong>, <strong>ignore</strong> the README at the site. All you have to do to
install the theme is to open the <code>*.terminal</code> file. That should be enough to
make it appear in the themes list in the preferences dialog, where you can set
it as default.</p>

<p><a href="http://ethanschoonover.com/solarized">Solarized</a> is a great general purpose theme and there are settings for many
text environments - I use it in Xcode, <a href="http://www.sublimetext.com/2">Sublime Text 2</a>,
<a href="http://www.eclipsecolorthemes.org/?list=all&amp;q=solarized">Eclipse</a> and even
<a href="http://www.vim.org/">Vim</a>.</p>

<p>Which, niftily, brings me on to my next section.</p>

<h2>Making Vim Pretty</h2>

<p>Much as I've rallied against <a href="http://www.vim.org/">Vim</a> over the years, <a href="https://twitter.com/vizio360">Vizio360</a>
and <a href="https://twitter.com/Rev_Kachowski">Rev. Kachowski</a> have now drugged me
sufficiently to admit that it's pretty damn nice really. If you can handle
memorising &pi; to 300 digits, then you should be fine with <a href="http://www.vim.org/">Vim</a>
shortcuts. On the other hand if you're like me, you may want to use a
<a href="http://www.viemu.com/a_vi_vim_graphical_cheat_sheet_tutorial.html">cheatsheet</a>.</p>

<p>However, we aren't here to learn, we're here to colourise. So, in order
to make Vim a bit more colourful on OS X, copy the example <code>vimrc</code> file
to your home directory:</p>

<pre><code>cp /usr/share/vim/vim73/vimrc_example.vim ~/.vimrc
</code></pre>

<p>Now you can enjoy pretty colours in Vim. If you want to add <a href="http://ethanschoonover.com/solarized">Solarized</a>
as your colour theme in Vim, I recommend installing the rather fantastic
<a href="https://github.com/tpope/vim-pathogen">pathogen.vim</a> in your .vimrc (<a href="https://github.com/tpope/vim-pathogen/blob/master/README.markdown">instructions</a>) and
then follow the instructions for "Option 2" in <a href="http://ethanschoonover.com/solarized/vim-colors-solarized">vim-colors-solarized README</a>.</p>

<h2>Making Nano Pretty</h2>

<p>If Nano is your Terminal text editor weapon of choice, then you can
enable syntax colouring by uncommenting the syntax files referenced in
<code>/etc/nanorc</code>. First, open it for editing:</p>

<pre><code>sudo nano /etc/nanorc
</code></pre>

<p>Move to the bottom of the file and then remove the <code>#</code> character
at the beginning of the lines which include other <code>*.nanorc</code> files. For
example, change:</p>

<p>``` bash /etc/nanorc</p>

<h2>Nanorc files</h2>

<h1>include "/usr/local/share/nano/nanorc.nanorc"</h1>

<p>```</p>

<p>To:</p>

<p>``` bash /etc/nanorc</p>

<h2>Nanorc files</h2>

<p>include "/usr/local/share/nano/nanorc.nanorc"
```</p>

<h2>Further Eyeball Licking via Homebrew</h2>

<p>For the next tip, I recommend using <a href="http://mxcl.github.com/homebrew/">Homebrew</a>
as the method of installation. If you aren't using <a href="http://mxcl.github.com/homebrew/">Homebrew</a>
yet, you probably should be. It's by far the <a href="http://mozidesign.com/2011/03/15/dinosaurs/">Most Awesome</a> package manager
available for OS X. So go install it:</p>

<ul>
<li><a href="https://github.com/mxcl/homebrew/wiki/installation">https://github.com/mxcl/homebrew/wiki/installation</a></li>
</ul>


<p>Installed? Good. Let us continue.</p>

<h2>Generic Colouriser</h2>

<p><a href="http://kassiopeia.juls.savba.sk/~garabik/software/grc/README.txt">Generic Colouriser</a>
is a great utility which can be used for colourising many different types of
output and log files. If you installed <a href="http://mxcl.github.com/homebrew/">Homebrew</a>
, installing grc is as simple as typing:</p>

<pre><code>brew install grc
</code></pre>

<p><strong>NOTE</strong>: If you followed the first tip and created a <code>.bash_profile</code>,
rather than appending the command to load grc to your <code>.bashrc</code>,
you want to append it to your <code>.bash_profile</code> file instead:</p>

<pre><code>echo 'source "`brew --prefix grc`/etc/grc.bashrc"' &gt;&gt; ~/.bash_profile
</code></pre>

<p>If you are confused as to why, it's because the logic Bash uses for loading
these files is non-obvious. For a good description of the load sequence, read
<a href="http://www.thegeekstuff.com/2008/10/execution-sequence-for-bash_profile-bashrc-bash_login-profile-and-bash_logout/">Execution sequence for .bash_profile, .bashrc, .bash_login, .profile and .bash_logout</a>
by Ramesh Natarajan.</p>

<p>After you have added that line to your <code>.bash_profile</code>, either start a new
session, or reload the profile:</p>

<pre><code>source ~/.bash_profile
</code></pre>

<p>Now when you use certain commands such as traceroute, the output should be
colourised:</p>

<p><img class="center" src="/images/traceroute-grc.png" width="622" height="422"></p>

<p>Or you can call <code>tail</code> and <code>head</code> using grc to colourise log output:</p>

<p><img class="center" src="/images/head-grc.png" width="512" height="156"></p>

<h2>That's all Folks!</h2>

<p>Well, that's all I have for now. If anyone has any other good ones,
stick them in a comment below.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
