<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: procrastination | Noise & Heat]]></title>
  <link href="http://noiseandheat.github.com/blog/categories/procrastination/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://noiseandheat.github.com/"/>
  <updated>2012-11-16T00:08:28+00:00</updated>
  <id>http://noiseandheat.github.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[David Wagner]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Aaaaaand, the hibernation ends]]></title>
    <link href="http://noiseandheat.github.com/blog/2010/05/aaaaaand-the-hibernation-ends/"/>
    <updated>2010-05-22T22:34:00+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://noiseandheat.github.com/blog/2010/05/aaaaaand-the-hibernation-ends</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img class="right" src="/images/01.jpg" width="200" height="130"></p>

<p>Well, what a pleasant hiatus that was. Almost 3 months. However, no more! I
shall get back to blogging random useless technical details about various
things. I know you missed me really.</p>

<!--more-->


<p>So, what's happening next? Well, firstly, I'm temporarily turning to the Dark
Side and getting a Nexus One. This shiny new toy should be in my sweaty paws
within the week. I'm thoroughly looking forward to breaking it. I may even try
some Flash programming on it, although I'm far more interested in the <a href="http://developer.android.com/sdk/ndk/index.html">Android NDK</a> at the moment. Since I
have no creative bones, I want to see how well it lends itself to running
<a href="http://www.box2d.org/">Box2D</a> (I know it's already been ported to NDK, but
what's the point of Open Source if you can't rewrite the wheel every couple of
weeks?).</p>

<p>After that, I may actually get around to finishing the shabby little
accelerated computation engine thingy I was writing for
<a href="http://www.adobe.com/devnet/pixelbender/">PixelBender</a> and
<a href="http://www.adobe.com/devnet/flash/">Flash</a>.</p>

<p>Maybe by mentioning these things somewhere, I'll actually get around to
finishing them…</p>

<p>Firstly, however, I'll have to tinker with Eclipse. I really don't like white
backgrounds and black text in a code editor. Plus, I like procrastinating and
putting off actual productive work.</p>

<p>While you are waiting for all those terribly exciting projects to appear, why
not go an learn guitar? You'll have time. Try
<a href="http://justinguitar.com/">http://justinguitar.com/</a> for nice course.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
