<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Curiosities | Noise & Heat]]></title>
  <link href="http://noiseandheat.github.com/blog/categories/curiosities/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://noiseandheat.github.com/"/>
  <updated>2012-11-16T00:08:28+00:00</updated>
  <id>http://noiseandheat.github.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[David Wagner]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[No Vodka Tampons, we're Scottish]]></title>
    <link href="http://noiseandheat.github.com/blog/2011/11/no-vodka-tampons-were-scottish/"/>
    <updated>2011-11-14T21:35:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://noiseandheat.github.com/blog/2011/11/no-vodka-tampons-were-scottish</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/File:Elements_of_a_tampon_with_applicator.jpg"><img class="right" src="/images/whisky_tampon.png" width="200" height="130"></a></p>

<p>So I've been thinking about this, and pending further evidence I'm going to
assume that the story about vodka soaked tampons (see
<a href="http://goo.gl/7bpv3">KPHO</a>) is rubbish. Every so often it seems to make the
rounds (see <a href="http://goo.gl/2u9Oe">Snopes</a>). Here's why I'm an unbeliever.</p>

<!--more-->


<p>A tampon will soak up about 15ml-18ml (see <a href="http://goo.gl/jSCOQ">About.com</a>)
of liquid which is a pathetic dram. Alcohol is not blood, but for this thought
experiment it'll do. I can test it later. Regardless, it's likely much less
than a shot.</p>

<p>In addition tampons are designed to retain liquid rather than release it, so
there's a reasonable chance that it wouldn't release the booze very quickly.</p>

<p>Now, as far as I can discover, a stomach absorbs about 20% of consumed alcohol
(see <a href="http://goo.gl/kqc7C">Brown University</a>), the rest is through your
intestine. For the moment I'll make the assumption that vaginal walls absorb
alcohol at a similar rate as the intestine. Although this probably isn't
accurate due to the the quantity of blood vessels, it doesn't matter because
the rumour generally also includes men who, it is whispered, stick it up their
bum.</p>

<p>It follows, I think, that if I drink a Polite Dram (about 35ml - 40ml), 80% of
that will end up in my intestines, which is 28ml - 32ml. That's about double
what this mythical Tampon Delivery Mechanism would offer. Also, drinking the
Polite Dram on an empty stomach (remember kids: eatin' is cheatin') will whap
that Double Tampon Quantity right into my intestine, an organ which exists to
diffuse things into my blood vessels and make embarassing noises during quiet
moments.</p>

<p>Therefore I conclude that ingesting a Polite Dram on an empty stomach may be
up to twice as efficacious as Tampon Delivery, plus it's easier to buy in
rounds. Have you ever tried getting a tampon in a pub? Those bloody machines
never work.</p>

<p>Right, pending volunteers for double blind tests, I'll get back to my coding
with a nice <a href="http://www.thebalvenie.com/en-%0Agb/ourRange_currentRange_signature.php">Balvenie Doublewood</a>. In a
<a href="http://www.whiskyglass.com/">glass</a>.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Cracking the Code]]></title>
    <link href="http://noiseandheat.github.com/blog/2010/10/cracking-the-code/"/>
    <updated>2010-10-09T23:53:00+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://noiseandheat.github.com/blog/2010/10/cracking-the-code</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Fact o' the day. Google's <a href="http://twitter.com/google/status/1251523388">first ever tweet</a> was:</p>

<p><blockquote><p>I'm<br/>01100110 01100101 01100101 01101100 01101001<br/>01101110 01100111 00100000 01101100 01110101<br/>01100011 01101011 01111001 00001010</p><footer><strong>Google</strong> <cite><a href='http://twitter.com/google/status/1251523388'>First Tweet</a></cite></footer></blockquote></p>

<!--more-->


<p>Which brings me to a little plaything I was asked to make for <a href="http://binaryday.co.uk/">Binary Day (10/10/10)</a>.
It turns messages into binary and vice versa. You can even tweet them which
leads me to believe that Google used the tool from the future just to make
that tweet. Very cunning of them.</p>

<p>For a quick translation their message, have a look at the <a href="http://binaryday.co.uk/?message=I'm%200110011001100101011001010110110001101001011011100110011100100000011011000111010101100011011010110111100100101110">binary day tool</a>!</p>

<p><em>[P.S. I'm hosting an alternative version at N&amp;H which will handle international
character sets: <a href="http://binary.noiseandheat.com/?message=I'm%201100110%201100101%201100101%201101100%201101001%201101110%201100111%20100000%201101100%201110101%201100011%201101011%201111001%20101110%20">http://binary.noiseandheat.com/</a>. Join the fun worldwide!]</em></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[How many bytes would a petabyte bite if a petabyte could bite bytes?]]></title>
    <link href="http://noiseandheat.github.com/blog/2010/02/how-many-bytes-would-a-petabyte-bite-if-a-petabyte-could-bite-bytes/"/>
    <updated>2010-02-23T13:46:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://noiseandheat.github.com/blog/2010/02/how-many-bytes-would-a-petabyte-bite-if-a-petabyte-could-bite-bytes</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>The CompactFlash association has just released a <a href="http://www.compactflash.org/pr/100222cf5prs.pdf">new specification</a>
for future CompactFlash cards. It involves big numbers. 144 petabytes big, to be
specific. But how big is that really?</p>

<!--more-->


<blockquote><p>144 petabytes = gigabytes.</p>

<p>Production quality 1080p video: <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/1080p#Production_standards">3 gigabits per second</a> which equals 0.375 gigabytes per second.</p>

<p>So, using that:</p>

<p><table border="0">
<tr><td>150,994,944 / 0.375</td><td>= 402,653,184 seconds of video</td></tr>
<tr><td></td><td>= 6,710,886.4 minutes of video</td></tr>
<tr><td></td><td>= 111,848.106. hours of video</td></tr>
<tr><td></td><td>= 4,660.337. days of video</td></tr>
<tr><td></td><td>= <strong>12.768 years of continuous video</strong></td></tr>
</table></p></blockquote>

<p>12 years of <strong>continuous</strong> 1080p video. Slap around 9 of those in a
camera and you can continuously video almost anyone for their <em>entire life</em>.
May as well be generous and use 10 - that should let you stick some low
quality sound recording of their entire life on it too.</p>

<p>I suspect the future will see an increased number of murders due to screenings
of family holiday videos...</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
