<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Codereview | Noise & Heat]]></title>
  <link href="http://noiseandheat.com/blog/categories/codereview/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://noiseandheat.com/"/>
  <updated>2012-11-16T00:01:02+00:00</updated>
  <id>http://noiseandheat.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[David Wagner]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Installing ReviewBoard on Amazon EC2]]></title>
    <link href="http://noiseandheat.com/blog/2011/11/installing-reviewboard-on-amazon-ec2/"/>
    <updated>2011-11-30T21:44:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://noiseandheat.com/blog/2011/11/installing-reviewboard-on-amazon-ec2</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Recently at <a href="http://www.huzutech.com/">HuzuTech</a> I updated our installation
of <a href="http://www.reviewboard.org/">ReviewBoard</a>, which is a great code review
tool. Rather than just update packages though, I decided to rebuild the
server for shits and giggles. Herein lies my method, just in case you want
to set one up yourself.</p>

<!--more-->


<h2>Pre-requisites</h2>

<p>This guide assumes that you have an AWS EC2 account set up, and that you are
comfortable with creating instances and SSH'ing into them. There are plenty
of other guides out there to take you through those basics.</p>

<h2>What You'll End Up With</h2>

<ul>
<li>1 (one) EC2 server micro instance running with a 32-bit Amazon Linux AMI</li>
<li>2 (two) VCS installed on the server: subversion and git</li>
<li>1 (one) Data Volume containing:

<ul>
<li>1 (one) ReviewBoard site</li>
<li>1 (one) PostgreSQL database</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>1 (one) Glowing feeling of a Job Well Done</li>
</ul>


<p>The precise security configuration and so forth for the instance is likely
to vary depending on what your preferred policies are.</p>

<h2>Creating The Instance</h2>

<p>Sign in to the EC2 web console and select "Launch Instance" for the region
you prefer. I'm using US East because it's cheap.</p>

<p>The following few screens show the Quick Launch instance wizard thing which
seems to have just sprung up on the site, but you should be able to work
out what to do in the normal/classic wizard.</p>

<p>The important points are:</p>

<ul>
<li>Use a Basic 32-bit Amazon Linux AMI</li>
<li>Use a micro instance</li>
</ul>


<p>Give your instance a sane name and create and download a new key pair for
it. You can use an existing pair, but I tend to use a new key pair for each
image for finer grained access control. Make sure it's the 32-bit Amazon
Linux AMI which you choose.</p>

<p><img class="center" src="/images/rb-setup-00.png" width="934" height="441"></p>

<p>In the next screen, you may find it useful to add termination protection
and check that it's selected a micro instance.</p>

<p><img class="center" src="/images/rb-setup-01.png" width="934" height="451"></p>

<p>Next, set up an new security group for it. You <strong>can't</strong> change the security
group later (although you can add and remove ports in the group), so make
sure you create a new one unless you are <em>certain</em> you want to share an
existing one. Make sure <code>SSH</code> and <code>HTTP</code> ports are open and accessible from your
<a href="http://www.google.co.uk/search?q=My+IP+Address">current public IP address</a>.
If in doubt, you can make the ports accessible from any address for the moment
by specifying a source of <code>0.0.0.0/0</code>.</p>

<p><img class="center" src="/images/rb-setup-02.png" width="934" height="465"></p>

<p>That's the basic instance set up. Click "Save details" and then you should
see the launching screen:</p>

<p><img class="center" src="/images/rb-setup-03.png" width="934" height="443"></p>

<p>Close it. Now create the volume to use for data. Expand the "Elastic Block Store"
menu at the left side if it isn't already and select Volumes. Click the
"Create Volume" button and make it about 1 GiB or so, depending on the
size of the repositories you'll store on it:</p>

<p><img class="center" src="/images/rb-setup-05.png" width="530" height="216"></p>

<p>Now all that remains to do is to attach it to the instance you just launched.
Select the new volume and click "Attach Volume" and attach it to your fresh
instance:</p>

<p><img class="center" src="/images/rb-setup-06.png" width="530" height="269"></p>

<p>That's the basic setup done. Now on to installing bytes.</p>

<h2>Setting Up The Instance and Data Volume</h2>

<p>SSH into your server:</p>

<pre><code>$ ssh -i ~/.ec2/tools-reviewboard.pem ec2-user@ec2-107-22-136-39.compute-1.amazonaws.com

       __|  __|_  )
       _|  (     /   Amazon Linux AMI
      ___|\___|___|

See /usr/share/doc/system-release/ for latest release notes.
There are 14 security update(s) out of 18 total update(s) available
[ec2-user@ip-10-116-186-53 ~]$
</code></pre>

<p>The first thing you're likely to notice is that the instance requires some
updates already, so we will install those.</p>

<p><em><strong>NOTE</strong>: for the rest of the
article, I'll just show the commands to run without showing the output, except
where the output is important or interactive. Also, the <strong>$</strong> at the start of
a line indicates a command to type - you don't type the dollar, but type the rest…</em></p>

<pre><code>$ sudo yum --assumeyes update
</code></pre>

<p>That should update the basic image to the latest versions of the pre-installed
packages.</p>

<p>Now, before we go any further, lets set up the data volume. You should
have already created a new volume and attached it to the ReviewBoard server
instance. If this is the first time you've used separate data volumes (something
you should really get into the habit of using), the thing to remember is that
it's sitting as a raw, unformatted block device initially. In order to use
it, it needs to be partitioned, formatted, and then mounted.</p>

<p>First, format it. I'm assuming that your device is <code>/dev/xvdf</code>. If it isn't,
adjust the instructions as appropriate. Run fdisk on the device. It's
interactive so the following few steps include the console output for clarity.</p>

<pre><code>$ sudo fdisk /dev/xvdf

Device contains neither a valid DOS partition table, nor Sun, SGI or OSF disklabel
Building a new DOS disklabel with disk identifier 0xb6d71f5e.
Changes will remain in memory only, until you decide to write them.
After that, of course, the previous content won't be recoverable.

Warning: invalid flag 0x0000 of partition table 4 will be corrected by w(rite)

WARNING: DOS-compatible mode is deprecated. It's strongly recommended to
         switch off the mode (command 'c') and change display units to
         sectors (command 'u').

Command (m for help):
</code></pre>

<p>Enter <strong>m</strong> in order to show a menu.</p>

<pre><code>Command action
   a   toggle a bootable flag
   b   edit bsd disklabel
   c   toggle the dos compatibility flag
   d   delete a partition
   l   list known partition types
   m   print this menu
   n   add a new partition
   o   create a new empty DOS partition table
   p   print the partition table
   q   quit without saving changes
   s   create a new empty Sun disklabel
   t   change a partition's system id
   u   change display/entry units
   v   verify the partition table
   w   write table to disk and exit
   x   extra functionality (experts only)

Command (m for help):
</code></pre>

<p>Enter <strong>n</strong> to create a new partition.</p>

<pre><code>Command action
   e   extended
   p   primary partition (1-4)
</code></pre>

<p>Enter <strong>p</strong> to create a primary partition.</p>

<pre><code>Partition number (1-4):
</code></pre>

<p>Enter <strong>1</strong>.</p>

<pre><code>First cylinder (1-261, default 1):
</code></pre>

<p>Press <strong>enter</strong> to select the default.</p>

<pre><code>Last cylinder, +cylinders or +size{K,M,G} (1-261, default 261):
</code></pre>

<p>Press <strong>enter</strong> to select the default. The actual value for the default will
depend on how large a volume you created with the Amazon web console. This
is a 2 GiB volume.</p>

<pre><code>Command (m for help):
</code></pre>

<p>Enter <strong>w</strong> to write the changes to the disk. The partition will be created
and you should see:</p>

<pre><code>The partition table has been altered!

Calling ioctl() to re-read partition table.
Syncing disks.
</code></pre>

<p>The next step is formatting the partition. Use <code>mkfs</code> to create a new ext4
partition:</p>

<pre><code>$ sudo mkfs -t ext4 /dev/xvdf
</code></pre>

<p>Now create an empty folder in <code>/mnt</code> for the partition, and edit <code>/etc/fstab</code>
to mount it on boot.</p>

<pre><code>$ sudo mkdir /mnt/rb.data
$ sudo nano /etc/fstab
</code></pre>

<p>The entry to add to fstab should look like this:</p>

<pre><code>/dev/xvdf     /mnt/rb.data   ext4    defaults    0   0
</code></pre>

<p>If you chose a different folder, filesystem or have it available on a different
device, remember to use your values here.</p>

<p>The final task is simply to mount the volume, and then run <code>df</code> to check
that it has mounted:</p>

<pre><code>$ sudo mount /mnt/rb.data
$ df -h

Filesystem            Size  Used Avail Use% Mounted on
/dev/xvda1            7.9G  1.1G  6.8G  14% /
tmpfs                 302M     0  302M   0% /dev/shm
/dev/xvdf             2.0G   67M  1.9G   4% /mnt/rb.data
</code></pre>

<p>If you don't see your volume in the <code>Mounted on</code> column, check all the
previous steps worked.</p>

<h2>Installing Lots Of Stuff</h2>

<p>Now to install all we need for ReviewBoard Cut and paste this full block
into the command line:</p>

<pre><code>$ sudo yum --assumeyes install \
    ant \
    ant-apache-regexp \
    autoconf \
    gcc \
    gcc-c++ \
    git \
    httpd \
    icu \
    java-1.6.0-openjdk-devel \
    libicu \
    libicu-devel \
    libjpeg \
    libjpeg-devel \
    libpng \
    libpng-devel \
    lucene \
    make \
    memcached \
    mod_wsgi \
    patch \
    postgresql \
    postgresql-devel \
    postgresql-server \
    python-devel \
    svn \
    telnet
</code></pre>

<p>Now to install the python prerequisite packages:</p>

<pre><code>$ sudo easy_install \
    python-memcached \
    pycrypto\&gt;=2.4.1 \
    psycopg2 \
    django-storages
</code></pre>

<p>Pyconfig will probably spew out lots of warnings, but it should be OK to
ignore those.</p>

<p>Next, install ReviewBoard:</p>

<pre><code>$ sudo easy_install ReviewBoard
</code></pre>

<p>Now you have a choice – install pylucene so that you can have full text
search in ReviewBoard, or skip it and just move on to setting up the database.</p>

<h2>Installing Pylucene <em>(optional)</em></h2>

<p>Although you don't need Pylucene installed, it's nice to have it because
of the search features it adds to ReviewBoard. However, it can be a bit of
a bugger to install, so although these instructions work for now, if they're
broken by the time you read this, you may want to skip it.</p>

<p>Brave? Then on-wards…</p>

<p>Create a folder to build and install Pylucene from, download and extract
the archive:</p>

<pre><code>$ mkdir pylucene
$ cd pylucene
$ curl apache.mirror.rbftpnetworks.com/lucene/pylucene/pylucene-3.4.0-1-src.tar.gz | tar -xvz
</code></pre>

<p><code>tar</code> may take a while to extract the large archive being fed to it, but
once it's finished, compile jcc:</p>

<pre><code>$ cd pylucene-3.4.0-1/jcc
$ sudo env JCC_JDK=/usr/lib/jvm/java-1.6.0-openjdk NO_SHARED=true python setup.py build
$ sudo env JCC_JDK=/usr/lib/jvm/java-1.6.0-openjdk NO_SHARED=true python setup.py install
$ cd ..
</code></pre>

<p>Now to build Pylucene. First you have to edit some values in the Makefile, so
open that:</p>

<pre><code>$ nano Makefile
</code></pre>

<p>And then paste these lines at the top of the very top of file, before the
block comment:</p>

<pre><code>JAVA_HOME=/usr/lib/jvm/java-1.6.0-openjdk
PREFIX_PYTHON=/usr
ANT=ant
PYTHON=$(PREFIX_PYTHON)/bin/python
JCC=$(PYTHON) -m -m jcc.__main__
NUM_FILES=3
</code></pre>

<p>Now you should be ready to build it:</p>

<pre><code>$ make
</code></pre>

<p>This can take a long time (30 minutes or so), so go get some tea. After it's
complete you can now install it:</p>

<pre><code>$ sudo make install
</code></pre>

<p>That's Pylucene dealt with. On to the database.</p>

<h2>Creating the ReviewBoard Database</h2>

<p>The database will also reside on the data volume. This setup assumes that
you only want one PostgreSQL cluster. I've no idea why you'd want more than
that, but if you do, you're advanced enough to figure out how to make the
next few steps fit into that configuration yourself.</p>

<p>First, create a folder for the database, and give it to the postgres user:</p>

<pre><code>$ sudo mkdir -p /mnt/rb.data/db/pg
$ sudo chown postgres:postgres /mnt/rb.data/db/pg
</code></pre>

<p>And now set that data location in the postgres conf file:</p>

<pre><code>$ echo "PGDATA=/mnt/rb.data/db/pg" | sudo tee /etc/sysconfig/pgsql/postgresql
</code></pre>

<p>With that sorted, we can now tell PostgreSQL to create the cluster:</p>

<pre><code>$ sudo service postgresql initdb
</code></pre>

<p>Next, we want to change the database authentication method for connections
from <code>127.0.0.1</code> in order to allow ReviewBoard to connect. To do this, edit
<code>/mnt/rb.data/db/pg/pg_hba.conf</code> and change the method used for <code>127.0.0.1/32</code>
from <code>ident</code> to <code>md5</code>:</p>

<pre><code>$ sudo nano /mnt/rb.data/db/pg/pg_hba.conf
</code></pre>

<p>Near the bottom of the file, change the line <code>host    all         all         127.0.0.1/32          ident</code>
to <code>host    all         all         127.0.0.1/32          md5</code>.</p>

<p>All that's left is to start it and then create the empty ReviewBoard database:</p>

<pre><code>$ sudo service postgresql start
$ sudo su postgres -c "createdb reviewboard"
</code></pre>

<p>Now create a database user for reviewboard. I'm going to be lazy here and create
them as a superuser because I can't be arsed setting up their correct priviledges.
Don't be as stupid as I am:</p>

<pre><code>$ sudo su postgres -c "createuser -sP reviewboarduser"
</code></pre>

<p>Be sure to give them a decently strong password.</p>

<p>Now, in case you have to reboot your server, you'll want to make sure things
start on boot. To do this, you can use <code>ntsysv</code>:</p>

<pre><code>$ sudo ntsysv
</code></pre>

<p>Use the cursor keys to move, space to select, and tab to move between areas.
Make sure you enable <code>httpd</code>, <code>memcached</code> and <code>postgresql</code>.</p>

<p>Just to make sure it's all running, reboot the instance.</p>

<pre><code>$ sudo shutdown -r now
</code></pre>

<p>This will kick you out of your session, but just give it a minute or two
and then log back in. The address of your server should still be the same
at this point, but if it isn't, you can find it again from the AWS web console.</p>

<p>After you've logged back in, check that the webserver is running to make sure
the <code>ntsysv</code> command above worked. The easiest way to do this is by using
telnet to request the default page from the local webserver:</p>

<pre><code>$ telnet 127.0.0.1 80
GET /
</code></pre>

<p>You should see a screed of HTML returned. If you see a connection refused or
timed out, go back to the <code>ntsysv</code> section above and try again. Note that
<code>ntsysv</code> doesn't start the services for you, it just marks them to start
on boot, so you have to perform that shutdown step to test it.</p>

<h2>Creating A ReviewBoard Site</h2>

<p>That's pretty much the server setup now. All that remains is to create a
review board site. There's a handy interactive script to do this. Create
a directory for the site and then run the interactive script:</p>

<pre><code>$ sudo mkdir -p /mnt/rb.data/www
$ sudo rb-site install /mnt/rb.data/www/reviewboard.huzutech.com
</code></pre>

<p>The script is fairly informative, but if you need more information, see
the ReviewBoard documentation for creating sites:</p>

<ul>
<li><a href="http://www.reviewboard.org/docs/manual/1.6/admin/installation/creating-sites/">http://www.reviewboard.org/docs/manual/1.6/admin/installation/creating-sites/</a></li>
</ul>


<p>Basically, the only thing to remember is that you are using a <strong>postgresql</strong> database,
<strong>memcached</strong>, <strong>apache</strong> and <strong>wsgi</strong>.</p>

<p>Give ownership of the web directory to Apache, and add the generated site
config to the apache conf folder, then restart apache:</p>

<pre><code>$ sudo chown -R apache:apache /mnt/rb.data/www
$ sudo ln -s /mnt/rb.data/www/reviewboard.huzutech.com/conf/apache-wsgi.conf /etc/httpd/conf.d/XX_reviewboard.huzutech.com.conf
$ sudo service httpd restart
</code></pre>

<p>Note that the link name starts with <code>XX_</code>. This is important so that it's
loaded in the correct order.</p>

<h2>Finished!</h2>

<p>That's it! You should be able to see your server if you visit the public
address in a web browser. There are several post setup things that you
probably want to do, such as setting up a proper vhost file, locking user
registration and setting up projects and repositories.</p>

<p>If you installed lucene, don't forget to add the lucene index updating cron
job to cron, otherwise you'll get errors when you try to search and it can't
find the search index files.</p>

<p>Check out the guides on the main <a href="http://www.reviewboard.org/docs/">ReviewBoard</a> website for more information
about all that. Then sit back and learn from all the glorious code reviews
you see rolling in.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
