<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: admin | Noise & Heat]]></title>
  <link href="http://noiseandheat.com/blog/categories/admin/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://noiseandheat.com/"/>
  <updated>2012-11-16T00:01:02+00:00</updated>
  <id>http://noiseandheat.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[David Wagner]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Throttling bandwidth on OS X]]></title>
    <link href="http://noiseandheat.com/blog/2012/02/throttling-bandwidth-on-os-x/"/>
    <updated>2012-02-03T22:35:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://noiseandheat.com/blog/2012/02/throttling-bandwidth-on-os-x</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Recently I started pushing a repository to GitHub only to find out it
was a couple of GB in size. Due to my <a href="http://www.virginmedia.com/">ISPs</a> network
connection being made of soiled tissue paper, dead earwigs and lost
hope, it quickly saturated it. This interrupted watching
<a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Breaking_Bad">Breaking Bad</a> on <a href="http://www.netflix.com/">Netflix</a>. Clearly something had to be done.</p>

<p>Enter <code>ipfw</code>.</p>

<!--more-->


<p><code>ipfw</code> is more generally thought of as a utility for managing firewall
rules on OS X, but it's also great for shaping traffic. Doing that is a
simple two step process: create an <code>ipfw pipe</code> for a data flow and then
configure how big that pipe is.</p>

<p>First, create a pipe which matches a flow of data. A pipe is a
combination of source address, destination address and optional matching
patterns. In my case I wanted to affect outgoing traffic to port 22
which is used by <code>ssh</code>, the program <code>git</code> generally talks to servers
with:</p>

<pre><code>$ sudo ipfw add pipe 1 ip from any to any out dst-port 22
</code></pre>

<p>I've been a bit lazy here by using <code>any</code> for the IP address fields. I
know that only my connection to github will be using <code>dst-port 22</code>. The
<code>from</code> IP address and <code>to</code> IP address may be written as a specifc IP, or
 a range of IPs using <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/CIDR_notation">CIDR notation</a>, instead of the <code>any</code> wildcard.
 I've specifically set the rule to only match <code>out</code> going traffic. If
 you want to control the flow of data in both directions, you would
 generally create an <code>in</code> pipe and an <code>out</code> pipe separately</p>

<p>Note that I've named this pipe <strong>1</strong>. This number is used to uniquely
identify the pipe when carrying out other operations on it. If you
create more than one pipe, be sure to use unique numbers for each one.</p>

<p>Next, we have to configure the pipe to control the data flow:</p>

<pre><code>$ sudo ipfw pipe 1 config bw 75KBytes/s
</code></pre>

<p>The <code>bw</code> setting ensures that data passing through pipe 1 is
transferring at most 75 KBytes per second. You can set this to whatever
value is suitable for your connection.</p>

<p>If you want, you can check what connections are being affected:</p>

<pre><code>$ sudo ipfw pipe list
00001: 600.000 Kbit/s    0 ms   50 sl. 1 queues (1 buckets) droptail
    mask: 0x00 0x00000000/0x0000 -&gt; 0x00000000/0x0000
BKT Prot ___Source IP/port____ ____Dest. IP/port____ Tot_pkt/bytes Pkt/Byte Drp
  0 tcp    192.168.0.100/61291  207.97.227.239/22     685   991700 31 43792   0
</code></pre>

<p>Finally, don't forget to remove the pipe when you no longer need to
limit the data transfer rate:</p>

<pre><code>$ sudo ipfw pipe delete 1
</code></pre>

<p>There are many other options in <code>ipfw</code> for shaping traffic, including
commands for dropping a certain percentage of packets (great for testing
game networking code), and you can limit the bandwidth to very small
rates which is handy for seeing how slow connections experience websites
you create. Check out the
<a href="https://developer.apple.com/library/mac/#documentation/Darwin/Reference/ManPages/man8/ipfw.8.html">man page</a>
for more details.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
